The fact that there is even a modicum of doubt
on whether or not the woman who shot Adjika Owens
should be criminally charged
is representative of the fact that racism continues
to plague so many systems in this country.
I don't want to hear y'all say,
well, why didn't she call the police?
I guess you've never been to Ocala.
So many of us do not look to the police for protection.
We also don't look to the police as allies
in our efforts for peacekeeping.
The sheriff is trying to paint Adjika as an aggressor
for coming over and knocking on this woman's door
after this woman assaulted her children,
called them racial slurs and cursed at them
and stole their property.
This reminds us that this country continues to feel
that Black people have no right to speak up for ourselves
and have no right to challenge
when we have been wronged by white people.
Adjika had every right to come over there
to discuss what had happened with her children
and she was murdered for it.
And the woman, her neighbor Susan Lawrence,
a 58-year-old white woman who lived in her complex,
should be arrested immediately.
She is a menace to society
and she took a mother away from four children
who was clearly showing that she was there to protect them.